SAMUEL IGBEKELE

CBN Estate 2, Satellite Town, Lagos (Ready-to-relocate)

+2348106010198 | samuelayo61@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/samuel-igbekele-44184171

www.github.com/XKolz, https://samuel-igbekele.netlify.app

SUMMARY

An experienced full-stack developer with over 4 years' experience in facilitating solutions with wide technology skills to leverage full-stack knowledge to analyze, design, and build interactive user-centered website designs and applications. Also possess experience in the installation and management of database servers. I am seeking to secure a position at a prominent IT organization focused on providing technology-related services and solutions, to utilize my practical knowledge in contributing effectively to the advancement of the organization while improving my experience.

RELEVANT SKILLS/STACK

Language: JavaScript, Typescript, Python, HTML & CSS, PHP, SQL, Java, C.

Libraries: JQuery, ReactJS.

Frameworks: NextJS, ExpressJS(NodeJS), NestJS, Django, React Native,

Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap.

API: Postman, Thunder Client, Rest Client, insomnia.

Software: Visual Studio, Xcode, Android Studio, Gitbash, PyCharmCE, Vmare

Workstation, Figma, Krita, Flutterflow, Microsoft Office.

Databases: phpMyAdmin, Microsoft SQL Server, MongoDB, Postgres, SQLite.

Version Controls: Git, GitHub, BitBucket, GitLab.

Web hosting platforms: Microsoft Azure, GCP

Web Servers: Apache
Containerization: Docker

Software Architecture: Client-Server, Layered, Monolithic.

EXPERIENCE

WORKPLACESTARS/ Software Engineer (Contract) | New York, United States | 05/2024 - 08/2024

- Designed, developed, and maintained responsive web applications using ReactJs, NextJs and Python, improving the user experience and enhancing overall functionality.
- Implemented performance optimizations that reduced page load times by 30%, leading to a smoother user experience and increased customer satisfaction.

- Worked closely with cross-functional teams, including UX/UI designers, product managers, and QA testers, to deliver high-quality software solutions aligned with business objectives.
- Led code reviews to ensure adherence to best practices and coding standards, and
- mentored junior developers, fostering a culture of continuous learning and improvement.
- Successfully integrated third-party APIs, such as payment gateways and social media platforms, to expand application functionality and enhance user engagement.

DEITYVILLAS/ Software Engineer | Atlanta, United States | 01/2024 - 07/2024

- Developed and maintained web applications and internal tools using ReactJS, and NextJS to streamline property management processes.
- Achieved a 30% improvement in website loading speed, elevating user experience and customer satisfaction.
- Engineered and managed backend services with Nodejs and ExpressJS, enhancing the functionality and performance.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to design and develop new features, ensuring alignment with business goals and user needs.
- Utilized version control systems (BitBucket) to manage codebase and facilitate team collaboration.
- Worked with various databases including PostgreSQL to store and manage property data efficiently.
- Conducted API testing with Postman to ensure robust and reliable integrations with external services.
- Performed regular code reviews and debugging to maintain high code quality and performance standards.
- Utilized project management tools to track progress, manage tasks, and communicate effectively within the team.

ZOJATECH/ Frontend Engineer | Lagos, Nigeria | 10/2023 - 06/2024

- Developed visually appealing web applications, ensuring performance, functionality, and consistent branding.
- Enhanced the performance of critical web features, leading to a 15% reduction in page load times and improved user satisfaction scores.
- Mentored and trained 3 interns during their onboarding, all of whom successfully contributed to project deliverable within their first month.
- Provided technical advice to teammates on 7 design projects, resulting in the implementation of innovative and user-friendly UI/UX enhancements.
- Collaborated effectively with cross-functional teams to translate ideas into tangible solution.

EDUCATION

BSc.(Ed.) Computer Science | 2019 | University of Ilorin, Kwara

CERTIFICATION AND PARTICIPATION

ALX CERTIFIED SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

Issued by: ALX Africa

Date Earned: November 2023

Certification ID: intranet.alxswe.com/certificates/ycJLZsHpfT

ALX ARTIFICAL INTELLIGENCE CAREER ESSENTIALS

Issued by: ALX Africa
Date Earned: April 2024

Certification ID: https://intranet.alxswe.com/certificates/hXMz8RELen

ALX VIRTUAL ASSISTANCE SKILLS

Issued by: ALX Africa

Date Earned: September 2024

Certification ID:https://intranet.alxswe.com/certificates/RTnMFp3rSB

• NYSC CERTIFICATION OF NATIONAL SERVICE | Oriade Local Government, Lagos | 2019-2020

Microsoft SQL SERVER DATABASE (in-view)

INTERESTS

ResearchTechnologyTravelFitness

Music ● Art

REFEREES

To be provided on request.